const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",i="civiledu",o=200,t=120,a=[{id:217,question:"An important characteristics of Democracy is",option:{a:"The absence of free press and mass media",b:"Unequal political rights",c:"Respect for principle of rule of law",d:"The absence of separation of powers between the   arms and levels of government"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:357,question:"Cultism can best be discouraged through",option:{a:"mentoring of cultists by the rich",b:"provision of jobs for cultists",c:"sensitization on the dangers of cultism",d:"establishment of cultists support groups"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:122,question:"........... is the verdict that results when a law court declares a defendant guilty of a crime",option:{a:"immunity clause",b:"conviction",c:"customary clause",d:"traditions"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:388,question:"Citizen’s compliance with tenets of the Nigerian National Pledge will enable the country to",option:{a:"receive reciprocal assistance",b:"witness value clarification",c:"get international aid",d:"experience development"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:314,question:"Mondays and Thursday are days meant for in between environmental sanitation exercise in ........... and .......... states respectively",option:{a:"Lagos and Edo",b:"Edo and Lagos",c:"Abuja and Lagos",d:"Delta and Lagos"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:191,question:"The function of vehicle inspection officer (VIO) is",option:{a:"ensuring the road wordiness of vehicle on the road",b:"protection of life and property",c:"collection of tax",d:"counting of votes cast at election"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:389,question:"Which of the following statements may be true about the behaviour of the candidates in the diagram?",option:{a:"The candidates are doing what is ethical",b:"Candidates involved in malpractice should be banned for life",c:"Their action can also affect innocent candidates",d:"Their misconduct will guarantee a reliable certificate"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:242,question:"Which of the following type of government is hereditary?",option:{a:"Democracy",b:"Oligarchy",c:"Monarchy",d:"Fascism"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:31,question:"One of the reasons most HIV/AIDS patients are 	reluctant to disclose their status is because of",option:{a:"the incurable nature of the ailment",b:"fear of social stigmatization.",c:"lack of sufficient public awareness",d:"shortage of health counsellors"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:326,question:"Driving, especially along the highway requires serious  ...........",option:{a:"concentration",b:"meditation",c:"concentration",d:"perambulation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:229,question:"The individual rights would be better protected if enshrined in the ..................",option:{a:"Courts",b:"Constitutions",c:"Bible and Quran",d:"National Newspapers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:22,question:"Conflicts are better resolved in the society through",option:{a:"tribunal",b:"litigation.",c:"dialogue",d:"the court"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:129,question:"One of the following is not a political party",option:{a:"PDP",b:"APGA",c:"ANPC",d:"CPC"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:102,question:"There are ............. local government in Nigeria",option:{a:"700",b:"714",c:"744",d:"774"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:432,question:"Orderliness in the society is good mainly because it",option:{a:"discourages poverty",b:"promotes peace and stability",c:"guarantees employment for youths",d:"ensures maximum rewards from leaders"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:204,question:"One of the ways to prevent the spread of HIV/AIDs is",option:{a:"Not to eat in fast food joints",b:"Not to shake hands with anybody",c:"To avoid any object contaminated with blood",d:"Sleep under a mosquito net"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:411,question:"Which of the following statements best describes Human Trafficking?",option:{a:"Recruitment of youths as casual workers",b:"Desperate desire by youths to travel abroad",c:"Buying and selling of humans for selfish purposes",d:"Transportation of gods and service through human portage"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:415,question:"A very important segment of the society which is distinct from government, business and home is the",option:{a:"civil society",b:"public service",c:"mass media",d:"traditional institution"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:85,question:"Nigeria is now hundred years since amalgamation which means she has celebrated — anniversary.",option:{a:"amalgamation.",b:"centenary.",c:"golden jubilee.",d:"independence."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:390,question:"Based on the above diagram, the candidates would not have cheated if",option:{a:"they were well-spaced",b:"there was an invigilator",c:"they were hardworking",d:"there was nobody to copy from"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:322,question:"General Murtala Mohammed was assassinated on his way to work in ..............",option:{a:"February 13, 1976",b:"June 12, 1993",c:"October 1, 1960",d:"June 8, 1998"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:367,question:"Youth empowerment promotes",option:{a:"self-reliance",b:"youthful exuberance",c:"pursuit of higher education",d:"foreign scholarship"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:299,question:"Nigeria celebrated her centenary anniversary in the ......",option:{a:"1954",b:"1960",c:"1963",d:"2014"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:136,question:"The process whereby an individual choose to favour a person who come from his family or tribe over other people or tribes is known as",option:{a:"stereotype",b:"ethnicity",c:"nepotism",d:"favouritism"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:182,question:"A manifesto refers to",option:{a:"the register of party members",b:"rejected ballot papers",c:"valid ballot papers",d:"Document containing the aims and programmes of   a political party"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:265,question:"Some years ago a popular Governor in one of the states in Nigeria was asked to mention some mineral 	resources from his state. He made mention of “Fanta, Pepsi, Coca cola. The governor is",option:{a:"right",b:"wrong",c:"illiterate",d:"unpatriotic"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:279,question:"A sovereign state is one",option:{a:"whose citizens are free to evade responsibility",b:"whose governments decisions are made independent of foreign interference",c:"which has a president and a prime minister",d:"where its citizens can speak without fear or favour"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:319,question:"The three larges and most influential ethnic groups in Nigeria are",option:{a:"Yoruba, Edo and Hausa",b:"Igbo, Iteskiri and Hausa",c:"Hausa, Igbo and Yoruba",d:"Fulani, Yoruba and Efik"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:150,question:"The colour of the Nigeria flag is ..............., anytime it 	is half masked it means that the nation is ...............",option:{a:"green white green - rejoicing",b:"white green white - mourning",c:"green white green - mourning",d:"green white blue - voting"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:153,question:"The National Assembly in Nigeria is primarily responsible for",option:{a:"executing laws",b:"Interpreting laws",c:"ratifying appointment",d:"making laws"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:399,question:"In order to avoid undue interference in the process of governance, there should be",option:{a:"clear cut separation of governmental powers",b:"proper fusion of governmental powers and functions",c:"more roles for traditional rulers in the governmental process",d:"additional responsibility for local government council"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:394,question:"The following cadre of students are the main target for campus cult membership except",option:{a:"students from wealthy homes",b:"students from influential parents",c:"bold and morally sound students",d:"wayward and fun-loving students"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:256,question:"Malaria fever can be transmitted through",option:{a:"hand shaking",b:"eating of unbalanced diet",c:"mosquito bite",d:"eating of bush meat such as bat and monkey"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:351,question:"“We the people of the Federal Republic of Nigeria” is usually the opening phrase of the preamble to",option:{a:"coup announcement",b:"government gazettes",c:"constitution",d:"mansard"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:296,question:"Public servants in Nigeria are expected to be .............",option:{a:"involved in politics",b:"non-partisan",c:"ambitious politically",d:"partial"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:408,question:"Which of the following is not a function of the National Drug Law Enforcement Agency (NDLEA)?",option:{a:"Applying and implementing all drug laws",b:"Arresting, investigating and prosecuting drug traffickers",c:"Undertaking the registration of companies dealing 	in drugs",d:"Carrying out enlightenment campaigns on drug trafficking"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:58,question:"One of the aims of citizenship education is to produce students with",option:{a:"creative skill.",b:"high sense of entrepreneurial skill.",c:"high sense of patriotism.",d:"manipulative skills."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:151,question:"Which of the following is used in gauging public opinion",option:{a:"Constitution",b:"Educational Institution",c:"Mass media",d:"Electoral college"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:407,question:"Cultism in tertiary institutions in Nigeria was originally introduced to",option:{a:"perpetuate the use of local gin and alcohol",b:"harass opponents of university administrators",c:"fight colonialism and oppressive rules",d:"promote inter-communal marriages."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:110,question:"The act of counting the numbers of people living in a country in order to determine the total numbers of 	people in a state is known as .......",option:{a:"election",b:"national population census",c:"voting",d:"rights"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:106,question:"One of the listed criteria qualifies one for election .......",option:{a:"certificate",b:"beauty",c:"height",d:"citizenship"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:179,question:"A coup d’etat is regarded as",option:{a:"A source of political legitimacy",b:"A manipulation of the constitution",c:"A constitutional way of changing the government",d:"an unconstitutional way of changing the government"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:356,question:"Which of the following statements is not correct?",option:{a:"Valid driver’s license must be obtained before attempting to drive",b:"Flowing garment can be worn on a motorcycle or bicycle",c:"Headlights should be used during unfavourable weather",d:"Drivers must not engage in distractive activities while driving"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:317,question:"Which of these tax below is paid by nearly everybody in Nigeria",option:{a:"Direct tax",b:"Excise tax",c:"Proportional tax",d:"Regressive"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:56,question:"The most effective approach towards the elimination of sexually transmitted diseases is by",option:{a:"abstinence.",b:"Casual sex.",c:"use of condom.",d:"use of drugs"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:79,question:"The public service structure of Nigeria is an offshoot of",option:{a:"America.",b:"British.",c:"Canada.",d:"India."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:212,question:"The armed forces and the police are part of the ........ organ of government",option:{a:"executive",b:"judicial",c:"legislative",d:"informative"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:225,question:"Membership of a state is known as",option:{a:"citizenship",b:"statism",c:"patriotism",d:"indigenousness"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:104,question:"Television and radio are example  of ......... media",option:{a:"print",b:"electronic",c:"advertising",d:"mass"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:84,question:"Which of the following is not a function of political parties?",option:{a:"Aggregation of opinion",b:"Educating the government",c:"Interest articulation",d:"Unifying factor."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:2,question:"Rule of Law means",option:{a:"supremacy of the law",b:"absence of legal immunity",c:"peace, order and stability",d:"obedience to any authority"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:142,question:"From the basic road traffic regulation pedestrians should not attempt to cross the road when the light are ............. and ...............",option:{a:"green and yellow",b:"green and red",c:"yellow and red",d:"red and yellow"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:362,question:"A major factor responsible for human trafficking is",option:{a:"hunger",b:"illiteracy",c:"greed",d:"joblessness"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:97,question:"The channel through which political parties make their program known to the people is ..............",option:{a:"canvassing",b:"campaigning",c:"convincing",d:"coronation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:209,question:"An indifference attitude towards political activities by the citizens of a state is termed",option:{a:"political apathy",b:"political unrest",c:"political ideology",d:"political disunity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:406,question:"Which of the following is not included in the stages of interpersonal relationship?",option:{a:"Rejuvenation",b:"Deterioration",c:"Termination",d:"Continuation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:98,question:"What arm of the criminal justice system is prison?",option:{a:"first",b:"second",c:"third",d:"none"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:146,question:"Political values are acquired in any given society through",option:{a:"Political re-orientation",b:"Political campaign",c:"Political socialization",d:"Political indoctrination"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:138,question:"Traffic lights are also known and referred to as",option:{a:"three directives light",b:"spotlight",c:"flow traffic directive",d:"informative sign"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:161,question:"Law made by military governments are called",option:{a:"decrees",b:"Bye-laws",c:"Edicts",d:"acts"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:409,question:"An individual who finds it difficult to control in-take of drug is known as drug",option:{a:"baron",b:"traffickers",c:"mogul",d:"addict"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:378,question:"Children that are not cared for are mostly prone to",option:{a:"criminal attitudes",b:"terminal diseases",c:"examination failure",d:"forced migration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:266,question:"If you were to be in the Governor’s shoes which of the following would you have chosen?",option:{a:"Miranda and seven up",b:"coca cola and Fanta",c:"petroleum",d:"stock, bonds and cash"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:115,question:"......... refer to a group of drugs that are inhaled in the form of a gas or solvent",option:{a:"hallucinogens",b:"stimulants",c:"inhalants",d:"gasoline"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:160,question:"The office responsible for announcing the result of an election is known as",option:{a:"ballot officer",b:"presiding officer",c:"Returning officer",d:"Electoral officer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:172,question:"A constitution that is very easy to amend is called a ...... constitution",option:{a:"rigid",b:"flexible",c:"an easy",d:"simple"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:397,question:"World AIDS day is observed on",option:{a:"20th May",b:"30th July",c:"27th August",d:"1th December"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:180,question:"Which of the following is an advantage of local government",option:{a:"Agents for money based politics",b:"electoral commissions",c:"training grounds for political leaders",d:"agents of pressure group"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:340,question:"Decrees are laws made by .............",option:{a:"the parliament",b:"the judiciary",c:"the military",d:"senators"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:404,question:"A responsible parent is someone who",option:{a:"cares and provides for the children",b:"indulges the children because of love",c:"works in order to receive salary",d:"employs house-helps to take care of the children"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:381,question:"Based on the monologue above, the best approach to curb moral decadence in the motherland is by",option:{a:"value re-orientation",b:"introducing war against corruption",c:"legalizing capital punishment",d:"sending corrupt officials on exile"},section:"Oh Motherland, you were a precious country, a beacon of hope and aspiration as well as toga of pride of your citizens at independence. However, today you are bedeviled with evil, engulfed in darkness and to say the obvious, at the edge of total moral collapse. Corruption, fraud, deception and dishonesty are prevalent; drug peddlers are having a field day. In schools and colleges, radicalism, prostitution, cultism, examination malpractice among other social vices are order of the day.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:100,question:"The responsibility of protecting past and present high ranking government officials falls on ...............",option:{a:"police",b:"army",c:"civil defense corps",d:"SSS"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:87,question:"One of the following is a country as well as a continent.",option:{a:"Africa",b:"Antarctica",c:"Asia",d:"Australia"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:170,question:"Which of these countries operate a unitary system of 	government",option:{a:"Nigeria",b:"U. S. A",c:"Ghana",d:"Britain"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:261,question:"On a particular day in 2014, the National flag was flown half mask. This act symbolizes",option:{a:"National tailors day",b:"National mourning",c:"Children’s day",d:"Golden jubilee celebration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:328,question:"The full meaning of NYSC is ..............",option:{a:"Now Your Suffering Continues",b:"Nigeria Youths Serving Christ",c:"National Youth Service Corps",d:"Nigerian Youth Service Corps"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:46,question:"A major lesson Nigerians could learn from the story is that",option:{a:"leaders can empower voters by giving them money",b:"security officials should use brutal force on citizens",c:"the underprivileged should not vie for elective positions",d:"greed and related vices can cause serious breach of  the law."},section:"Chief Bilisi was a prominent politician and honourable minister in Kantoga Republic. He had sponsored several candidates to power and made them to swear oath of allegiance to him. In return, they awarded contracts and offered financial and material assistance to him at the expense of the public. This had resulted in the non - provision of social amenities. These were some of the grievances the community had against him for which a mob gathered in front of his house shouting and hauling abusive words at him. They did not stop at that as they vandalized property and obstructed vehicular movement",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:173,question:"In a democratic government, political sovereignty is vested in the",option:{a:"legislature",b:"elite",c:"executive",d:"electorate"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:393,question:"Which of the following factors does not affect interpersonal relationship?",option:{a:"Communication",b:"Withdrawal",c:"Compatibility",d:"Forgiveness"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:331,question:"Those eligible to partake in the scheme are those",option:{a:"Those seeking for admission into the higher institutions",b:"Who have successfully completed their studies from higher institution .eg. college of education, 		     polytechnic & university",c:"Who are looking for something to keep them busy",d:"Who are from poor family background"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:257,question:"Plenty of money in the society, not backed by commensurate productive activities can lead to",option:{a:"deflation",b:"inflation",c:"National developmental",d:"cashless society"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:36,question:"From this dialogue, it is very likely that Wanja will be exhibiting the following characters except",option:{a:"disobedience to constituted authority",b:"truancy and perpetual lateness to school",c:"hospitable attitude towards people",d:"arrogance and unruly behaviour."},section:"Ada:      Wanja, where are you going to in this ungodly hour of the night? <br> 	Wanja:   I am heading towards my usual joint to enjoy myself <br>	 	Ada:       Which joint?<br> 	Wanja:   XYZ. Night Club, where I take marijuana and alcoholic beverages. I really want to be high 			      tonight so that when people see me tomorrow, they will fear and respect me.<br> 	Ada:     Remember, people who work under the influence of hard drugs and alcoholic beverages are prone to either psychiatric problems or premature death. Softly young man, imbibe good - natured character, you have the world at your feet and a destiny to fulfil. Pray you will not be the architect of your own misfortune.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:231,question:"Which of these characteristics of the civil service ensure continuity of government?",option:{a:"Neutrality",b:"Permanence",c:"Bureaucracy",d:"Loyalty"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:159,question:"Citizenship is acquired by an alien through",option:{a:"registration",b:"birth",c:"Conferment",d:"Naturalization"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:12,question:"Youth empowerment is best described as the",option:{a:"training given to individuals for acquiring means livelihood",b:"practice of engaging in prospective career",c:"provision of subsidized meals to the citizens by government,",d:"mobilization of citizens for political rally."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:321,question:"NUC and NBA stands for ......... and ......... respectively",option:{a:"National University Commission and Nigeria Bar Association",b:"Nigeria Bar Association and National University Commission",c:"National Union Congress and Nigeria Basketball Authority",d:"National Utilities Commission and Nigeria Bar Association"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:37,question:"Which of the following may result from Wanja’s habit?",option:{a:"Humility for elders",b:"Criminality in the society",c:"Advocacy for hard drugs by NGOs",d:"Excellent performance in school"},section:"Ada:      Wanja, where are you going to in this ungodly hour of the night? <br> 	Wanja:   I am heading towards my usual joint to enjoy myself <br>	 	Ada:       Which joint?<br> 	Wanja:   XYZ. Night Club, where I take marijuana and alcoholic beverages. I really want to be high 			      tonight so that when people see me tomorrow, they will fear and respect me.<br> 	Ada:     Remember, people who work under the influence of hard drugs and alcoholic beverages are prone to either psychiatric problems or premature death. Softly young man, imbibe good - natured character, you have the world at your feet and a destiny to fulfil. Pray you will not be the architect of your own misfortune.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:206,question:"The process of enlightening or training citizens on their rights and responsibilities is known as",option:{a:"Workshop training",b:"Citizenship Education",c:"Political Education",d:"Citizenship Rights"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:418,question:"A situation whereby someone is obliged to inform a superior about his actions and decisions for the purpose of control is",option:{a:"probity",b:"self-discipline",c:"accountability",d:"fair play"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:302,question:"Which of these is NOT undesirable in the society",option:{a:"cultism",b:"terrorism",c:"patriotism",d:"vandalism"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:386,question:"Based on the above story, which of the following would Dr.Fajir not be allowed to do while in prison?",option:{a:"Voting during elections",b:"Engaging in hard labour",c:"Participating in prison fellowship",d:"Writing examination"},section:"Dr. Fajir was the Minister of Works and Urban Development in the Gambia Republic. As such, he was entrusted with the public fund so that his ministry could construct new roads and rehabilitate the existing ones. Unfortunately. Dr Fajir embezzled the money entrusted in his care and siphoned same to his foreign accounts. This led to the deplorable conditions of roads in the Republic. The Crime Commission arrested and prosecuted him accordingly. Subsequently, he was given the opportunity to be defended by lawyers of his choice in a Court of Law. However, he was found guilty and sentenced to 15 years imprisonment with hard labour without the option of a fine. In addition, he forfeited all his ill-gotten wealth to the Republic.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:260,question:"The first known outbreak of Ebola was in ................",option:{a:"2014, in Sierra Leone",b:"1976, in a remote village near the Ebola River in Congo",c:"2014, in port Harcourt, Nigeria",d:"Enugu, during the Nigeria - Biafra war"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:391,question:"In which year did the United Nations General Assembly adopt the Universal Declaration of Human Rights?",option:{a:"1945",b:"1946",c:"1947",d:"1948"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:281,question:"Juvenile delinquency refers to",option:{a:"active youths participation in sports",b:"wrong doings by the youths",c:"Refusal to worship God by the youths",d:"Urban Rural migration by the youth"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:400,question:"Red-tapism is one the shortcomings of",option:{a:"private enterprise",b:"public service",c:"non-governmental organization",d:"pressure groups"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:49,question:"Cooperation between one country and another can be described as",option:{a:"bilateral",b:"international",c:"multilateral",d:"multinational."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:262,question:"Vehicles are expected to continue with their journey when the traffic light shows ...............",option:{a:"Red",b:"Blue",c:"Yellow",d:"Green"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:310,question:"If six political parties contest for an election (A, B, C, D, E, F), what is the probability that party C will wine the election",option:{a:"1/3",b:"1/4",c:"1/6",d:"1/2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:341,question:"The document containing the aims and programs of a political party is called ...........",option:{a:"register",b:"manifesto",c:"memorandum of party",d:"party library"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:66,question:"Which of the following system of government advocates equitable distribution of wealth?",option:{a:"Aristocracy",b:"Capitalism",c:"Plutocracy",d:"Socialism"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"},{id:290,question:"Which of these categories of people stand the greatest risk of contacting the Ebola virus .........",option:{a:"Lecturers and students in the school",b:"Health workers and their family members",c:"Hunters and their family members",d:"b and c above"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:241,question:"A problem commonly faced by most people living with HIV/AIDs is of",option:{a:"Stigmatization",b:"Non availability of drugs",c:"Government insincerity",d:"Lost of appetite"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:297,question:"HIV and Ebola can be contacted through contact with",option:{a:"Non infected person",b:"contaminated medical equipment such as needles and syringes",c:"Very sick person",d:"Healthy reptiles"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:332,question:"The age limit for the service is ..............",option:{a:"25",b:"35",c:"30",d:"18"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:307,question:"Civic Education is also known as ....................",option:{a:"Organizational Structure",b:"Citizenship Education",c:"Customers Opinion",d:"Government Policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:215,question:"Which of the following can cause Human Trafficking in a country",option:{a:"poverty, youth unemployment and greed",b:"Sound education and proper counselling",c:"Social and economic contentment",d:"B and C above"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:337,question:"Some years to come, when you become the President of Nigeria, which of the options below will you choose 	to eradicate porzverty in the country",option:{a:"carry all the poor people away from Nigeria to another country so when there are no poor people poverty will be gone forever",b:"print plenty Naira Notes and give millions to every Nigeria",c:"Import plenty Agricultural and Manufactured goods",d:"None of the above"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:330,question:"One of the main objectives of establishing the NYSC is to .................",option:{a:"Enable the youths to have some practical experience 		     after schooling",b:"Forster National unity",c:"Engage the young graduates because “Idle mind is the devil’s workshop”",d:"Create employment for the young graduates"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:26,question:"Political apathy often leads to",option:{a:"low level of participation",b:"good governance",c:"political stability",d:"low literacy level"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:230,question:"What is the minimum age for voters in Nigeria",option:{a:"15",b:"20",c:"18",d:"50"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:385,question:"According to the above story, the open trial of Dr. Fajir and his representation by lawyers of his choice in a court of competent jurisdiction is an indication of",option:{a:"respect for habeas corpus",b:"freedom of expression",c:"respect for human rights",d:"freedom of legal representation"},section:"Dr. Fajir was the Minister of Works and Urban Development in the Gambia Republic. As such, he was entrusted with the public fund so that his ministry could construct new roads and rehabilitate the existing ones. Unfortunately. Dr Fajir embezzled the money entrusted in his care and siphoned same to his foreign accounts. This led to the deplorable conditions of roads in the Republic. The Crime Commission arrested and prosecuted him accordingly. Subsequently, he was given the opportunity to be defended by lawyers of his choice in a Court of Law. However, he was found guilty and sentenced to 15 years imprisonment with hard labour without the option of a fine. In addition, he forfeited all his ill-gotten wealth to the Republic.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:205,question:"Nigeria became independent in ........... and a Republic in ................ Respectively",option:{a:"1963 and 1960",b:"1960 and 1963",c:"1954 and 1960",d:"None of the above"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:152,question:"In Nigeria, The agency mainly responsible for the maintenance of internal peace and security is the",option:{a:"Army",b:"Navy",c:"Civil  defense corps",d:"Police"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:119,question:"........ is the type of parenthood where a different couple raise a particular child that is not their own",option:{a:"helicopter parent",b:"foster parenthood",c:"slow parenting",d:"different parenthood"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:350,question:"The administrative class in the public service is to",option:{a:"implement policies",b:"formulate policies",c:"veto policies",d:"oversee policies"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:234,question:"The organ of government which are normally fused in a military regime are the",option:{a:"judiciary and legislative",b:"civil service and executive",c:"legislative and executive",d:"legislative and judiciary"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:162,question:"The ultimate aim of political parties is to",option:{a:"implement people oriented programmes",b:"acquire and exercise power",c:"increase the political awareness of the electorate",d:"formulate and implement policies"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2012"},{id:370,question:"Rule of law is limited by the following except",option:{a:"state of emergency",b:"habeas corpus",c:"illiteracy",d:"immunity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2016"},{id:210,question:"For which of these can someone be arrested while driving on a high way",option:{a:"driving and laughing",b:"driving and singing",c:"driving and eating or receiving phone call",d:"driving and crying"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:88,question:"In a parliamentary system of government, the powers of the executive is vested in the office of the",option:{a:"minister.",b:"premier",c:"president.",d:"prime minister."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2014"}],n={message:e,subject:i,status:200,total:120,data:a};export{a as data,n as default,e as message,o as status,i as subject,t as total};
